#### About Me

I am a creative, clear-thinking business leader with a deep technical background and a dedication to optimizing customer outcomes utilizing the latest software solutions. I have worked for GE since 2008 and developed my technical and leadership capabilities through training courses and world-class leadership programs (Edison Engineering Development Program (EEDP) and Accelerated Leadership Program (XLP)).

### Education

2010 - 2013 Marquette University - Milwaukee, WI Master of Science in Computing - GPA: 4.0 2005 – 2010 Grand Valley State University - Allendale, MI Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering - GPA: 3.235

### Experience

June 2008 – Present

**GE Aviation – Cincinnati, OH** 

Integration Director, M&A - Aviation Digital, XLP - 1 year

- Led the integration of 2 acquisitions over a 12-month span, focused on talent development, process and product synergies, culture adoption, product roadmap expansion and mentorship and coaching of ~100 employees.
- Facilitated the development of a robust non-core product divestiture strategy to strengthen the growth portfolio of core competencies
- Identified opportunities to grow and synergize with GE Aviation Digital Senior Enterprise Software Architect - GE for GE Predix, XLP - 1 year
- Closed financial issues with GE Digital around price/cost/billing for infrastructure and services usage in GE Aviation
- Drove GE Digital prioritization of features based on architectural gap definition with Predix Platform and needs of GE Aviation applications
- Led 5-member scrum team on feature development for Digital Thread Engineer Senior Embedded Software Engineer – 3 years
- Led software development on multiple projects including planning, forecasting, earned value management and milestone tracking for teams of 2-6 people
- Implemented a more agile approach to software projects
- Led continuous improvement initiative for group, saving over \$1MM over 2 years
- Instructor and mentor for Edison Engineering Development Program Embedded Software Engineer, EEDP – 3 years
- Embedded software developer utilizing VxWorks, Linux and bare metal OS
- Implemented device drivers on multiple platforms with multiple compiler types
- Designed and created automated testing/continuous integration plans Systems Engineering Intern – 2 years
- Developed an illustrated replaceable parts list tool which saves GEHC ~\$5.5MM
- Prepared all necessary paperwork for release including 3 patent applications

June 2014 – July 2016

Michigan Labs – Grand Rapids, MI

Consulting Mobile Application Developer

- Performed full-lifecycle application development Android and iOS
- Released 4 applications GiveAWow, 360Recognition, Light of Life, 91.3 WCSG

Aug 2011 –

**Grand Valley State University – Grand Rapids, MI** 

Dec 2011 Adjunct Faculty

• Lab instructor for Introduction to Digital Systems (EGR 226)







# **Training**

2016 – 2018 GE Accelerated Leadership Program (XLP) – Cincinnati, OH

Cloud Computing, Cybersecurity, Blockchain, Unconscious Bias, Cash Management, Effective Communication, Think Like an Airline, Leading Virtual Teams, Management Simulation

2013 – 2016 GE Aviation - Grand Rapids, MI

Foundations of GE Leadership, Project Management at GE, Leadership Development Course, Green Belt Certification, Engineering@GE

2010 – 2013 **GE Edison Engineering Development Program (EEDP) - Grand Rapids, MI**Accredited, company taught courses in advanced software engineering topics

## **Technical Skills**



#### References

Steve Walters
Business Program Manager - XLP
steve.walters1@ge.com
+1.513.410.0773

Charlie Nixon
Senior Embedded SW Manager
Charles.Nixon3@ge.com
+1.616.915.8617

John Oldham
Executive – Business Operations
john.oldham@ge.com
+1.214.263.2891